[ THUNDER CRASHING ]
[ RAIN FALLING ]
[ GASPS ]
What the f- - ?
Fuck . What the fuck ?
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
Oh . What the fuck ?
What the- - ?
What the fuck ?
[ PANTING ]
What the- - ?
What the fuck ? !
God !
Hello ? !
Fuck .
What the- - ?
[ GASPS ]
Hello , Seth .
[ GRUNTS ]
I wanna play a game .
Right now , you are feeling helpless .
This is the same helplessness ... Help !
you 've bestowed onto others .
But now , it 's onto you .
Let me out . Some would call this karma .
I call it justice .
Now , you served five years
of what should have been a life sentence for murder .
A technicality gave you freedom ,
but it inhibited you from understanding
the impact of taking a life .
Today , I offer you true freedom .
In 30 seconds ,
pendulum will drop
far enough to touch your body .
Within 60 seconds ,
it will cut you in half .
To avoid the pendulum ,
all you have to do is destroy the things that have killed :
your hands .
You must insert your hands
and push the buttons to start the devices before you .
Your bones will be crushed to dust .
Will you destroy the things
that have taken life in order to save one , Seth ?
Make your choice .
[ CLOCK TICKING LOUDLY ]
[ GRUNTS ] No .
No .
[ GEARS GRINDING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
No !
Fuck ! Come- -
It was an accident !
[ GASPS ]
Please .
[ WHIMPERING ]
Okay . Fuck you .
[ SCREAMING ]
Okay . Okay . Okay .
Okay .
[ WHIMPERING ]
Fuck !
[ SCREAMING ]
[ BONES CRUNCHING ]
[ CRYING OUT ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ ENGINE STOPS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
Oh , my- -
I did it ! I- -
Oh , my God .
[ SCREAMING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ SOFTLY ] I did what I was supposed to do .
[ GROANS ]
[ GASPS ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
MAN : Let me see your hands . Let me see your fucking hands .
MAN 2 : Where is my daughter ? You- -
Fuck .
What the f- - ?
Jesus .
[ DOOR SHUTS ]
[ BEEPING ]
JIGSAW [ ON RECORDER ] : Hello , Agent Strahm .
If you 're hearing this ,
then you 've finally found what you 've been looking for .
But is the discovery of my body ... enough ?
Or will your insatiable hunger to uncover the truth
push you deeper into the abyss ?
Heed my warning : Do not proceed .
For this room can either be your sanctuary ,
or it can be your grave .
The choice is yours .
Fuck you .
[ SHRIEKS ]
Ahh .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ GASPS ]
Hey !
Help !
[ SCREAMS ]
No .
[ EXHALES , INHALES ]
[ SIRENS WAILING , TIRES SCREECH ]
Go ! Go !
You 're okay .
[ MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Where 's my dad ?
He 's gonna be okay .
Where 's my mom ? Where 's my mom ?
FISK : Hoffman .
I got it . I got it .
What the f- - ? Over here .
You okay to walk ?
What the hell , man . What happened ? Where 's Rigg ?
Tried to help . He didn 't make it .
Nobody made it .
PARAMEDIC : We got a live one .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ AMBULANCE SIREN WAILING ]
[ KEYBOARD TYPING ]
[ RINGS ]
Hello ?
Right away .
Ms. Tuck .
Have a seat .
It 's nice to meet you , Mr. Feldman .
Why am I here ?
I represent your ex-husband , John .
In the event of his death ,
I was instructed to contact you .
You can understand my surprise
when I found out
who he really was .
John left something for you .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ QUIET GASP ]
If you 're watching this , Jill ,
I 'm long gone from this world .
You are my heart , you always have been .
You always ... will be .
I 'm not going to try to , uh , explain , uh .
my actions of late .
Suffice it to say
that I find it difficult to forgive myself
for what happened at the clinic .
[ SOBBING ]
I permitted , indeed , encouraged
your decisions regarding the people there .
I saw danger , and I , uh- -
I should have acted sooner .
I 'm leaving you a box today ,
and its contents are of ...
grave importance .
Even though you and I don 't always see
eye to eye on everything ,
I deeply believe in you ,
and I believe that you will know
what to do with these materials .
[ SNIFFLES ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ LOCK OPENS ]
MAN : I wanna thank you all for coming here today .
And I 'd like to be the first to say
that the Jigsaw murders are over .
[ APPLAUSE ]
MAN 2 : Wonderful . That 's good news .
The officers who gave their lives
are being honored here today .
But today , I 'd like to offer a special honor
to the detective who 's been on this case
right from the beginning .
Who proved through hard work and dedication
that the people who died did not die in vain .
Today , we honor
the newly promoted Detective Lieutenant ...
Mark Hoffman .
[ AUDIENCE APPLAUDS ]
MAN 3 : Congratulations .
HOFFMAN : Thank you so much .
[ MIKE FEEDBACK RINGS ]
Uh , thank you . Thank you very much .
Um ... [ CLEARS THROAT ]
... uh , throughout this ordeal ,
if we 've learned anything , it 's that
human life is sacred .
And we 've learned that every day ...
life should be cherished .
Justice ...
is the backbone to every ...
peaceful society .
And I believe that true justice has been served .
[ PHONE RINGS ]
[ SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO CHATTER ]
Detective Hoffman . You 're wanted at the hospital .
It 's about Agent Perez .
Thank you .
Hello , Agent Perez ,
and welcome to the world
that you have long studied .
Heed my warning , Agent Perez .
Your next move is critical .
Open the door .
PEREZ : What is that ?
[ CHOKING ]
[ LAUGHS ]
All right . I got you .
I got you .
[ PHONE RINGING ]
I 'm truly sorry about Agent Perez .
[ RASPY VOICE ] She said your name , you know .
Last thing she said was " Detective Hoffman . "
Why 'd she say that ?
Why 'd she say your name ?
I don 't know .
No ?
How 'd you walk out of that building ?
How did you ?
On a gurney with a fucking hole in my throat .
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
Look at you .
Couple of scratches
and a story about how your arm straps broke .
Jigsaw doesn 't make mistakes .
Is this you theorizing again ?
'Cause Jigsaw 's dead .
I 'm not talking about him . I 'm talking about you
and your whole crooked department .
My department 's gone . They 're all dead .
There 's no one left .
Besides you .
Been chasing Jigsaw from the beginning ...
and I got him .
So unless you 've got something else to say ...
back the fuck off .
Read the papers . I saved that little girl .
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ PHONE RINGING ]
[ SIGHS ]
Sorry about Agent Perez .
Shouldn 't you be resting ?
I 'm fine , Erickson .
No , you 're not , Peter . [ COUGHS ]
That 's why I put you on medical leave .
I was supposed to die in that trap .
You never should have been there without backup .
I wanna talk to Jill Tuck one last time .
You 're no longer handling the case , Peter .
What ?
Read it .
Over a dozen dead bodies were recovered
at the scene , two of which were cops .
Jigsaw 's dead . How many lives did I inevitably save ?
By endangering yourself and others .
You 're off the case .
On whose orders ?
Mine .
I 'm sorry , Peter . It 's over .
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ GASPS ]
Oh , my God .
Oh .
What is this ?
Hey . Don 't move .
What did you do to me ?
I didn 't do anything .
It 's Jigsaw .
What ?
MAN 1 : I knew this was gonna happen to me .
This is what he does .
No , it- - It 's not Jigsaw .
He 's dead .
Haven 't you watched TV lately ?
Yeah , well , whoever it is ...
they 're watching us .
To make sure we follow the rules .
Which are what ?
MAN 2 : I wouldn 't do that if I were you .
Unless you want your head to pop off like a dandelion .
How do you know that ?
Because I have eyes .
One pull-pin starts the timer for all of us .
You won 't wanna do that
unless you know how it works , now , would you ?
You 're starting to freak me out , dude .
[ BUZZING ]
JIGSAW : Hello , and welcome .
From birth , you 've all been given
the advantages of few others .
Yet through poor moral decisions ,
you 've used these advantages to selfishly further
only yourselves at the expense of others .
Well , today , this singular way of thinking
will be put to the test .
Today , five will become one , with a common goal of survival .
You are all connected .
A cable runs through your collar devices .
It can be pulled so tight
that you will be decapitated on the mounted razors .
The only way to remove the collar
is with the keys from the glass boxes
on the pedestals before you .
However , if one of you moves to retrieve a key ,
the 60-second timer will begin for you all .
In choosing how to react to this situation ,
your lifelong instincts will tell you to do one thing ,
but I implore you to do the opposite .
Let the games begin .
Somebody has to die .
WOMAN 1 : No , no , no . It says , " Don 't listen to your instincts . "
That means don 't go for the keys .
You fucking nuts ?
How are we supposed to live if we don 't ?
It 's testing our endurance .
We 've gotta move , babe .
That timer 's connected to those jars .
No , it didn 't say anything about those jars .
They could be nothing . WOMAN 2 : They 're nail bombs .
Homemade . Probably C-4 .
How the fuck do you know that ?
MAN 2 : She 's a fire inspector .
She 's seen all kinds of demented shit .
How do you know me ?
Hey , man , she 's asking you a question .
How do you know her ?
How do you know her ? ! Answer me !
Look , let 's just keep our cool .
Okay , we can figure this out .
We 're all here for a reason .
Okay ? And we 're all connected , as the message said .
We just need to- -
What did you do ?
You go first .
[ GROANS ]
It- - It said that we were all born with advantages .
Right ? That means we 're all from money .
I 'm not . And neither am I.
Hey , nice fucking try , Nancy Drew .
Well , then , what does it mean ?
We all did something wrong with an advantage
we were given from birth .
That doesn 't have to mean money .
What are you not telling us ? Huh ?
You know about her .
What do you know about the rest of us ?
Would you fucking talk to me ?
Relax .
I am fucking relaxed !
It 's a game , tweaker .
Get it ?
The less you know about me , the better .
The reason why you fucked up your charmed existence
is pretty obvious to everyone , isn 't it ?
Fuck you . Fuck you .
Been playing with matches again , have we ?
Fuck all of you and your fucking plan .
[ WOMEN SCREAMING ]
[ TICKING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Fuck ' em .
[ COUGHING , CHOKING ]
Ah !
[ ALL GRUNTING , CHOKING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ CRIES OUT ]
[ WOMAN 2 SCREAMING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ WOMEN GASP , SHRIEK ]
Unless you wanna be shredded when those nail bombs go off ,
I suggest we move on .
What are you doing ?
Being smart .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ DIALING ]
[ PHONE RINGS ]
Special Agent Strahm 's office .
This is Detective Hoffman . Is Agent Strahm available ?
He 's not . But I can connect you to Special Agent Erickson .
He 's handling all inquiries .
Please .
[ RINGING ]
ERICKSON : You 've reached the voice mailbox
of Special Agent Erickson .
Please leave a message .
[ BEEPS ]
Ah , yeah , this is Detective Hoffman .
I needed to discuss something with Agent Strahm ,
but I can 't seem to track him down .
Uh , could you give me a call ?
It would be greatly appreciated .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ BEEPS , DOOR UNLOCKS ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
[ SIGHS ]
There you are .
[ TYPING ]
Sister .
[ EXHALES ]
ERICKSON : Peter .
Cowan , uh , take this to Analysis .
Right away , sir .
What are you doing here ?
Just , ah , grabbing some stuff from the office .
I 'm- - I 'm taking your advice .
Taking some time off , huh ? Yeah , well ,
I- - I have to heal up , you know .
Mm-hm .
You know , I 'll keep in touch . I 'll see you around .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ FAINT YELLING ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ LOCKS DOOR ]
Hoffman .
We got another body .
Looks like another Jigsaw victim .
You up for this ?
Yeah .
FISK : Typical bio . Murder convict .
Served five years . Just released last month .
HOFFMAN : I know him .
His name 's Seth Baxter .
My sister 's ex-boyfriend .
This is the guy that murdered your sister ?
HOFFMAN : He was sentenced to 25 years .
Got it reduced to five on a technicality .
Well , then I 'd say justice was served .
You killed him .
Made it look like a Jigsaw trap .
I got you .
[ PANTING ]
Not yet !
Don 't close the door . It 'll set off the timer .
MAN 1 : Do you know that for sure ?
Educated guess .
What we need to do is figure out who everyone is .
Well , we know that the dead woman
worked for the fire department .
Not anymore . She got canned a month ago .
MAN 1 : How the fuck do you- -
How the fuck do you know that ?
You 're responsible for this ?
She had her fucking head cut off !
I 'm closing the door . I 'm gonna close the fucking door !
Just be quiet !
Please .
All right , what 's your story ?
I work for the Department of City Planning .
Married ? Kids ?
No . And no .
Your turn .
Uh , you 're not gonna tell them about ... Daddy ?
My dad is ...
Richard Gibbs .
The owner of the Cougars ?
He 's been trying to build
a new stadium for years .
Little did he know ,
all he had to do was wait
for his daughter to get a job
in City Planning .
And you . Hm ? What about you ?
What sort of shady shit have y-you been up to , hm ?
I 'm a senior V.P.
for a real estate development company .
S-so you 're boring too , hm ?
[ CHUCKLES ]
The Marshvard Group .
Yeah , you can 't get a permit in this town
without going through the Department of City Planning .
Right ?
No , you can 't .
What about you ?
Ah- - Ah ... no wife .
No kids that I know of and- - And ...
no job .
Trust fund baby . Anyone surprised ?
So fucking sick of your self-righteousness , man .
It 's your turn .
I 'm an investigative journalist for The Herald .
The Herald ?
That 's your massive accomplishment ?
You work for a gossip rag ?
Bite your fucking tongue .
What the hell are in those jars ?
Let 's do this fucking thing before the bombs go off .
[ BEEPS ]
[ RINGS ]
[ GROANING ]
Fuck !
JIGSAW : Hello , and welcome to the next lesson .
These walls hold four chambers .
These chambers are for safety .
However , to access them , a key is needed .
But only three of the keys will fit the locks .
These keys are in the glass jars
hanging from the ceiling .
Move quickly , though , because when the clock ticks down ,
the explosives in the corners of the room ...
will detonate .
With only three points of safety ,
which of you will be the odd man out ?
Make your choice .
Fuck .
[ WHIMPERS ]
[ CRIES OUT ]
Fuck , it 's blank . I need a shape .
[ GRUNTS ]
Get your hands off that . You 're not going anywhere .
[ CRIES OUT ]
[ GROANS ]
Stop it !
Get a clue , you fucking bitch .
It 's survival of the fittest .
[ WOMEN SCREAMING ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
Blank .
Shit .
I got it . Got it .
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ GLASS BREAKING ] [ GROANS ]
Yes .
Better luck next time , rich boy .
[ CRIES OUT ]
Survival of the fittest , my ass !
[ GROANS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Wait . [ GRUNTS ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ REMOVES ELASTIC BAND ]
[ GASPS ]
HOFFMAN : Is everything going all right with Detective Kerr
in the Seth Baxter case ?
Yeah . Good .
Fisk . You keep me posted .
Will do .
Good .
STRAHM : After Seth ,
you were involved in every investigation .
[ SIGHS ]
When did you first meet Jigsaw ?
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ]
[ DOORS OPEN ]
[ DISTANT SIREN WAILING ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ INDISTINCT MUSIC PLAYING ON HEADPHONES ]
[ SIGHS ]
WOMAN [ ECHOEY ] : Stop it . Stop it !
Don 't !
[ DOG BARKING ] WOMAN : Heel !
Heel , I said !
Don 't provoke him !
Asshole !
Jesus Christ ! Come on , Peewee . Come on !
Come on , Peewee ! Peewee .
Shit .
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ]
Do you mind ?
Going up ?
Yes , thank you .
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGING ]
What floor are you going to ?
[ GRUNTING ]
I think we 're both going to the same place .
[ LEATHER CREAKING ]
You know why you 're here , don 't you ?
They say imitation
is the sincerest form of flattery .
Hm . But I find it somewhat distasteful ...
to be given credit for work that 's not mine .
Especially inferior work .
Like you , I know what it 's like to lose family .
I know what it 's like not to
be able to protect loved ones .
It 's a powerless feeling .
No , I wouldn 't do that .
Hair trigger .
What do you see ?
Hm ?
Vengeance can change a person .
Make you into something
you never thought you were capable of being .
But unlike you , I 've never killed anyone .
I give people a chance .
You call this a chance ?
We 'll see .
Our game 's just begun .
Our game ?
You don 't even know me .
Oh ... I know you .
I 've followed you as you 've pursued me .
I know you . I know about your sister .
I know how you cared for her .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
I know she was your only family .
Leave me alone !
No !
You sit in bars until closing .
You drink so you can sleep .
You stagger to your car ,
and then you start in all over again the next day .
Then I discovered what you do for recreation .
[ SCREAMING ]
Mm-hm .
You can dispense justice
and give people a chance
to value their lives in the same moment .
And by the way ...
the blade on your pendulum was inferior .
If you want a true edge ...
you have to use tempered steel .
Tempering 's better for the long haul .
You in this for the long haul , detective ?
I 've been a cop for 20 years .
Is that long enough for you ?
Then you and I both know the statistics
for repeat offenders in this city .
67.5 percent of criminals
are back in prison within three years .
What do you want from me ? !
So you might look at what you did to Seth
as a kind of public service .
[ CHUCKLES ]
She was my only family .
He didn 't deserve a chance .
He was an animal ! Everybody deserves a chance !
You didn 't see the blood !
You didn 't see what he fucking did to her !
Killing is distasteful ...
to me .
There is a better ,
more efficient way .
[ PICKS UP CHAIR ]
What do you see- - ? Look !
What do you see ?
Tell me what you want .
I want to know if you have
what it takes to survive .
[ GASPS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ CLICKS ]
[ GASPS , BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Fuck you .
You see , it 's a different method
that I 'm talking about .
If a subject survives my method ,
he or she is instantly rehabilitated .
Now , you want a chance ? Hm ?
You want a chance ?
I 'll give you a chance .
I am the man you call Jigsaw .
It 's your duty to bring me in ,
but I know who you are
and I know what you 've done .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
So this is blackmail .
No , no , no , no , no .
This is redemption .
Just giving you an option . That 's all .
Now , you can arrest me ...
but doing so , your life ends as you know it .
Or ...
you could explore ...
a method of rehabilitation ...
that 'll permit you to sleep at night .
Or I could kill you right now .
But you 're not a true killer .
That 's your dilemma . And the information
that I have on you is exactly where it needs to be .
And it will be released
in the event of my disappearance .
They 'll never believe your word over mine .
You willing to take that risk ?
Risk of ruining your own life
in order to protect a corrupt legal system
that puts murderers back on the streets ?
How would your sister feel ?
You 're at a crossroads , detective .
Make your choice .
[ DROPS RAZOR ]
STRAHM : Did you help Jigsaw get all of ' em ?
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
ERICKSON [ ON PHONE ] : Detective Hoffman , this is Special Agent Erickson .
You had something you needed to discuss about the Jigsaw case ?
Yes , I stopped by Agent Strahm 's room
tonight at the hospital ,
but he wasn 't there .
I hope he 's all right .
Oh , yeah , he 's fine .
Agent Strahm was theorizing about the possibility
of an additional accomplice to Jigsaw ,
other than Amanda Young .
Someone who might be currently unknown .
Did he ever mention anything like that to you ?
No . But then again , I 'm new to the case .
Yeah , well ,
maybe you could get him to contact me
at his earliest convenience .
Uh , will do .
And , uh ... in your theorizing ...
who exactly did you suspect
would be an accomplice ?
Well , he suspected someone on the inside .
Someone with access .
It 's an interesting theory .
Detective ...
what do you say we reconnect in the morning ?
You got it . [ HANGS UP ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ BEEPS , LOCK OPENS ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ GRUNTS , WOMEN COUGHING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ PANTING ]
WOMAN 3 : Dead .
That guy was an asshole , but he was smart .
We could 've used him .
Yeah , well , someone had to die .
Would you rather it had been you ?
[ COUGHING ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
How 'd they get you ?
[ MAN CRYING OUT ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ YELLS ]
[ GROANS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ CRASH ]
[ GLASS CLINKS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Screw you !
I 'm gonna kill you .
I 'm gonna kill you ! Ah !
[ GRUNTING ]
I 'm gonna kill ...
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ FOOTSTEPS APPROACH ]
JIGSAW [ ON TAPE ] : Hello , Paul .
Did you cut yourself because you truly wanted to die ,
or did you just want some attention ?
Tonight , you 'll show me .
If you want to live ,
you 'll have to cut yourself again .
[ PAUL SCREAMS ]
How much blood will you shed
to stay alive , Paul ?
[ PAUL SCREAMS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
HOFFMAN : I didn 't expect to feel any remorse .
The heart cannot be involved .
Emotionally , there can be nothing there .
It can never be personal .
Let 's go .
No .
You 're not done yet .
Tonight , you will see the difference between killing
and rehabilitation .
There is another detective ...
that you should be aware of .
His name 's Tapp .
He 's smart , and he 's getting closer .
I know who he is .
I need you to lead him to someone for me .
A doctor .
A healer who needs some healing .
TAPP : Is this yours , doctor ?
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
You supplied these police files , didn 't you ?
You 're assuming this is gonna
play out the way you want it .
I assume nothing .
I anticipate the possibilities ,
and ... I let the game play out .
Then why do you need Amanda in the game ?
To ensure that the rules are followed .
She won 't make decisions for anyone .
She 'll just ...
offer choices .
Little to your left .
[ CLICKING ]
That leaves a lot to chance .
If you 're good at anticipating the human mind ...
it leaves nothing to chance .
[ CLICKING ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
It 's time .
Jesus Christ .
WOMAN 1 : Great . More bombs .
All right . What did you do to get here ?
I- - I did something ,
and a bunch of people were killed .
I didn 't mean to .
They 're still dead , s- -
That 's why you 're here ? Yeah .
Shouldn 't you have gone to jail for something like that ?
Nobody else knows .
Somebody does .
I didn 't kill anybody , if that 's what you 're asking .
I wasn 't .
I grant building permits .
And yeah , some people might have been
more deserving than others ,
but you know what ? That 's the business .
So if someone tells you different ,
well , then , they 're just stupid .
Or naive . Or both .
MAN : Bullshit .
You take bribes . You 're a fucking liar .
You cheat people . That 's not nice .
Yeah , well ...
I 'm sure she 's not exactly Mother Teresa either .
No , I 'm not .
I build condos in one of the most
densely populated cities in the country .
You don 't put up a new building
without tearing down a few old ones .
So we 're all bags of shit that deserve to be here .
That 's good . That 's great .
Fucking great .
Is- - Is that what you think this is ?
You don 't think there 's any other connection ?
No , I do .
I do . And I don 't give a shit .
Close the fucking door . We have to hear the rules .
Hello , and welcome .
You must all be eager to learn
the next important lesson in your transformation .
The game before you is designed
to bridge the gap between you all .
In order to open the five locks on the door out of this room ,
the five electrical circuits powering them
must be closed .
The only way to do this is to find a way
to connect all five cords to the bath water .
Close the circuits , and the door will open .
But you must work quickly , for in three minutes ,
an electrical current will surge through this room ,
locking the door forever .
Who will bridge the gap ?
The choice is yours .
Jesus Christ .
It 's not gonna reach . How the fuck are we gonna do this ?
Come on !
You 're gonna get in the tub ...
and we 're gonna connect the five cords to you .
But y-you 're gonna kill me too .
Get in . Yeah , I-I 'm more of a shower guy .
I don 't think I 'm gonna do that right now .
Get in the fucking tub . Fuck you , you bitch .
You get in the fucking tub .
[ GRUNTS ]
No , don 't do it .
Please , no .
[ BOTH GASP ]
[ GROANING ]
You killed her . You fucking killed her .
I didn 't trust her .
Jesus Christ . What is it with you two ?
Just shut up and help me with the body .
[ BEEPING ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
Wait , wait . No . Don 't let your body touch hers .
[ GRUNTING ]
Oh , my God , it 's a hook .
Stick it in her head , or we don 't get out .
Just do it .
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ TYPING ]
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
Come in .
Sir . Miss Jill Tuck .
Good evening .
I 'm Special Agent Erickson .
Thank you for seeing me so late in the day .
Not a problem .
That will be all . Thanks .
Thank you .
Please , have a seat .
So ...
what do you need from us ?
I think I 'm being followed .
Well , that sounds more like police work , Miss Tuck .
I don 't think they can help me .
Because ?
Because it 's you . The FBI .
I don 't understand .
It started when John was first identified
as the Jigsaw killer .
It didn 't surprise me then , but I 'm still being followed .
By who , Miss Tuck ? Who would be following you ?
I think it 's the agent who interrogated me .
Agent Strahm .
And why would he be following you ?
I don 't know .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
Who else have you told about this ?
Only you .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ JOHN COUGHING ]
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
HOFFMAN : What 's going on with Amanda ?
Didn 't you tell me the only way
to truly offer enlightenment ...
is by detaching emotionally ?
[ COUGHING ]
But you can have something Amanda doesn 't :
anonymity .
That 's the greatest protection .
That 's what I 've given you .
I need you to set up a game ...
that may not be entirely clear to you right now .
But I assure you that the people being tested ...
are part of something much larger .
They 're connected .
So in the end ...
all the pieces will fit together ...
and it 'll be clear .
[ WOMAN SCREAMING ]
Amanda will fail you . [ COUGHS ]
We 'll see .
WOMAN : What are you doing ? What are you doing ?
[ WOMAN GROANING ]
What 's this ?
It 's time to play a game .
[ WOMAN YELLING ]
WOMAN : Help !
Help me ! What is this ?
What is this ? Please .
[ COUGHS ]
WOMAN : Why are you keeping me here ?
What is this place ? What is this place ? !
[ WOMAN GROANING ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
We were all supposed to die .
[ GUNSHOT ]
He 's just fucking testing you !
[ MAN YELLING ]
Where is my daughter ?
Help !
He didn 't make it .
Nobody made it .
You were supposed to be the hero .
[ SIRENS WAILING ]
[ GROANS ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ CAR ALARM BEEPS ]
[ BEEPS ]
[ DIALING ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ PHONE RINGS ]
Peter , where the hell are you ?
Hello ?
[ DIALING ]
[ RINGS ]
[ BEEPS ]
You 've reached the voice mail for Special Agent Peter Strahm .
Leave a message .
[ BEEPS ]
Cowan . I wanna put a locator on Strahm 's mobile phone .
Right away , sir .
Call me right back .
Right . [ HANGS UP ]
[ TYPING ]
[ BEEPING ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
What the hell is that ?
It 's our next nightmare .
There are blades in here .
Oh , it 's connected to the door .
When the beaker fills up , the door opens .
Fills with what ?
Blood .
Our blood .
I think an arm is supposed to
go in there to fill the beaker .
Wait . W-why can 't we just use the water from the other room ?
No , the slots are closed .
We have to stick our arm in to keep them open ,
but then they 'd get stuck .
And we need to close that door .
So , what ?
We fight to the death , and the , uh ...
one gets to freedom with the other person 's blood ?
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
Wait . Wait , wait , wait .
Do you still have the keys from that first room ?
Yeah .
Try one of them on that door .
It won 't work . No , no , i-it might .
This one has a keyhole .
It- - It 's not even the same lock .
Wait , w-why are there five slots in this machine ?
Shouldn 't there only be one ?
[ DROPS KEYS ]
They all would have worked .
[ MEN CHATTERING ]
[ CAR STARTS ]
[ TIRES SCREECHING ]
[ BEEPING ]
There you are , Strahm .
All right . I got him .
[ TIRES SCREECHING ]
[ CLOCK BEEPING ]
[ GAGS ]
I don 't think this is a good idea .
The tub wasn 't meant for one person .
We- - We were supposed to hold one cable each
and suffer a small shock .
It was meant for five people .
They all were . Every game .
We only needed one key in the first room .
They all worked , and any one of them
would have opened every collar .
In the second room , the three tubes were large enough
for more than one person .
We were supposed to work together so we all survived .
That 's the game .
" Your lifelong instincts will tell you to do one thing ,
but I implore you to do the opposite . "
Oh , God . Whoops .
Yeah . Big fucking whoops .
[ EXPLOSION ]
[ BOTH GRUNTING , COUGHING ]
Hello , and welcome .
This journey has been one of discovery ,
and hopefully , you 've discovered
the whole is greater than the sum of its parts .
The human body , for instance ,
is an astoundingly durable creation .
It contains approximately 10 pints of blood ,
yet it is still able to operate with just half of that .
The device before you is one of sacrifice . [ COUGHING ]
A sacrifice of blood .
In order to open the door ,
the beaker must be filled to the marked level .
A level that is of no coincidence .
This amount can come from any one of you .
That does not matter . What does matter is time .
For in 15 minutes , if the beaker is not filled ,
the bombs will explode ,
and the doors will be sealed forever .
So now I ask you , how much blood will you give
in order to survive ?
[ MOTOR RUNNING ]
Fuck ! Fuck .
All right ... so one person can fill the beaker
with 10 pints of blood and die .
Or two people can fill it
with 5 pints ...
and maybe live .
What are we gonna do ?
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
MAN : I lied .
I know the investigative journalist in there .
His name is Charles .
He was writing a story about what I did .
What did you do ?
A dealer gave me ...
an ounce of heroin to burn down an abandoned building .
But it wa- -
Oh , God . It wasn 't abandoned .
There was eight people in there .
Eight people ... died .
And- -
And the- - The feds got involved .
And I got caught . But I made a deal , and my dad got me off .
But the guy who hired me disappeared ,
and nothing happened .
Nothing happened .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
Th-that 's how she knew me .
That woman in the tub .
The fire .
It 's what connects us .
The fire inspector who wrote the bogus accident report .
The city planner who pushed through
the residential permits . The- -
The journalist that buried the investigative story .
The rich-kid junkie who was the patsy .
And the real estate developer who set it all in motion .
We killed eight people and stole a property ,
and nobody cared .
Nobody cared ?
Eight people and their families cared !
The feds cared ! Look at my fucking arm !
I cared ! I cared !
But you didn 't face justice .
None of us did .
W-w-why did they all do it ?
Why ? W-was it for money ?
This was your plan ? You were the one behind it ?
There was eight people still living in that building .
You had to know that . Did you know that ? !
You 're a monster .
So are you .
We both deserve to be here .
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
I can 't do this alone . Look at me .
I can 't do this alone . I can 't . Okay . Okay .
[ MACHINERY WHIRRING ]
We have to go on three .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
One .
Two !
Put your hand in the hole !
[ GROANING ] Yes .
[ DOOR BANGS ]
Three !
[ BOTH SCREAMING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ BOTH GROANING ]
[ BOTH SCREAMING ]
[ BOTH GRUNTING , SCREAMING ]
JIGSAW [ ON TAPE ] : Hello , Agent Strahm .
If you are hearing this , then you have once again
found what you are looking for .
Or so you think .
Your dedication is to be commended .
But I ask you if you have learned anything
on your journey of discovery .
As the old adage goes :
" Fool me once , shame on you . Fool me twice , shame on me . "
The situation you find yourself in is one of trust .
So I ask you , Special Agent Strahm ,
have you learned to trust me ?
The only way to survive this room
is by entering the glass box before you .
Pain will be incurred ,
but you have a chance of survival .
[ CLICKS OFF , GASPS ]
[ WOMAN GROANING ]
[ DOOR CLANKS , MACHINERY TURNS OFF ]
[ GROANING ]
We did it .
We won .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ GRUNTING ]
I got you . You motherfucker .
[ WOMAN MOANING ]
Drop it !
I said , drop it !
[ HOOK CLINKS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Who did this to you ?
We won .
We worked together . We were connected .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
I need immediate medical assistance ,
1293 Sandburst Drive .
[ MOUTHS DIALOGUE ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ RINGING ]
[ CELL PHONE BUZZING , RINGING ]
[ GASPS ]
Jesus , Peter .
[ STRAHM GRUNTING ]
Tell me how to open it .
How do I open it ? !
[ CLICKS ON ]
JIGSAW [ ON TAPE ] : However , if you choose not to ,
you will never be heard from again .
Your body will never be found .
You will simply vanish .
I ask you , Special Agent Strahm ,
have you learned enough to trust me ?
Will you heed my warning ?
For if you do not ... Fuck you .
... this room will forever be your tomb .
And my legacy will become yours .
JOHN : If you 're good
at anticipating the human mind- -
I think I 'm being followed .
Who would be following you ?
I wanna talk to Jill Tuck one last time .
He suspected someone on the inside .
- -it leaves nothing to chance .
We were all supposed to die .
[ SCREAMING ]
You were supposed to be the hero .
[ SHUTTERS CLICKING , APPLAUSE ]
[ GEARS GRINDING ]
JIGSAW [ ON TAPE ] : Make your choice .
Cowan .
Yeah , this is Erickson .
ERICKSON : I want you to put out an APB .
Suspect 's name is Peter Strahm .
Yeah , that 's right .
Special Agent Peter Strahm .
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Tell me how to stop it , you son of a bitch !
[ GUNSHOTS ]
I know who you are !
I know !
[ BONES CRUNCHING ] [ SCREAMING ]
[ ¶ ¶ ¶ ]